Let's look at this spreadsheet.
我们看看这份表格
We have some ticker symbols in this column here and then a bunch of financial data,
这一列是一些股票代码 另外还有很多财务数据
then we'll get to in a short while.
稍后会用到这些数据
Looking at this ticker symbol,
看看这些股票代码
we can see that each ticker symbol is repeated a few times.
每个股票代码都有重复出现
We want to create as part the data validation is a drop-down list that
我们现在想要创建数据验证的下拉列表
contains only one occurrence of each of these ticker symbols.
列表里每个股票代码只出现一次
To get started, we're going to use pivot tables.
首先我们要用到数据透视表
Well, there are many ways to create data validation drop-down list.
创建数据验证的下拉列表有多种方法
This is one of the ways.
我们介绍的只是其中一种
So, we select ticker symbols,
先选择所有股票代码
you go insert, fill the table,
前往 “插入” - “数据透视表”
we've selected the cell already,
我们已经选择了相应的单元格
and we say new worksheet,
选中 “新工作表”
and it creates a pivot table here for us.
数据透视表就创建好了
We select ticker symbol,
勾选 "股票代码" (ticker symbol) 的选项
and it shows up under the rows,
会在 "行" (Rows) 下面显示
and you can see any repeated occurrences of each ticker symbol had been eliminated,
可以看到每个股票代码不再重复出现
and each symbol shows up only once.
而是都只出现一次
We need access to this unique list of names.
我们需要获取这个不存在重复内容的名称列表
I'm going to go ahead and paste it in here,
复制粘贴到这里
and then once I've pasted and I'm going to go ahead and select it again,
然后 再次选中这个列表
and use name box to give this list a name called company list.
在左上角的名称框里 把列表命名为 "company_list"
So, I'm going to have the selector,
这样 在后续操作中 我们就可以利用选择器
go to name box here and go to company list.
定位名称框 再定位 "company_list"
Once I've done that, I can reference this list by
完成这个操作后 我在不同公式中输入这个名称
simply calling this name in my formulas.
就能引用这个列表
We can now go ahead and create a new worksheet here.
现在 我们可以继续创建新工作表
We're going to call it data validation.
新工作表命名为数据验证 (data validation)
I'm going to type in ticker symbol because I want this to show up next to that,
这一格输入 "股票代码" (ticker symbol)
and then in this cell,
然后在这个单元格填入内容
I'm going to go Data, Data Validation.
首先要前往 "数据" - "数据验证"
You have the option to choose various criteria.
可以选择允许特定标准下填入的值
So, I'm going ahead and select a list,
在这里选择 "序列" (list)
and as a source,
在 "来源" (source)一栏
I'm going to reference back to this list here,
引用这个列表
and I can see it automatically filled into named box,
于是 该单元格就自动填入了之前名称框里的列表名称
and I go ahead and click Okay, and there you have it.
点击确定就可以了
You have a data drop-down menu that only references each of these names separately.
数据下拉列表就创建好了 选中其中一个名称 便只显示与之相关的内容
Another trick I just want to mention is that if you find
还有一个技巧
that you're having problems with the data range it's not showing up correctly,
如果在设置数据范围的时候出现问题 没法正常显示
you can go to the formula tab at the top,
可以选择顶部的 "公式" (formula) 标签
and you can go to Name Manager,
然后点击 "名称管理器" (Name Manager)
and here you can actually see all named boxes that you have,
便能看到所有的名称框
and it tells you which file it's referring to,
以及对应引用的文件
and you can confirm which ones you want to delete,
可以在此确认需要删除的名称、
which ones you want to edit,
需要编辑的名称、
or you can use the edit option to do that and correct the reference,
或者点击 “编辑” (edit) 按钮来纠正
which sheet did refers to.
其引用的工作表
So, this is also an option if you're having some trouble with
可以考虑采用这个方法来解决
the Data Validation. See you in the next video.
数据验证中遇到的问题 下次见！